<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephanie Hamilton</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/</link>
    <description>This is the personal website of Stephanie Hamilton, graduate student at the University of Michigan</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 22:10:23 -0700</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/hello/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi! I’m Stephanie, a high-energy-physicist-turned-astronomer working toward my
Ph.D. at the University of Michigan. I’ve had a non-linear path to becoming an
astronomer, even though astronomy has been my passion since about the sixth
grade. Better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to find myself studying the Solar System, and more specifically the
small objects that orbit within a donut-shaped ring farther out than Neptune. While
this isn’t what I’d pictured myself studying when I began graduate school, I
honestly wouldn’t want to be studying anything else! These small, seemingly
insignificant bodies in the distant reaches of the Solar System actually hold
the key to unlocking its entire history! The much larger gas giant planets
easily fling them about, so by discovering many of them and watching how they
move, we can try to make educated guesses as to what types of interactions
happened in their pasts. I think that’s what I find so cool and
exciting about my research – we are pushing the limits of the best telescopes
and cameras on Earth to search for objects that are a fraction of the size of
Earth and farther away than Pluto or the New Horizons spacecraft. It’s truly amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my time so far in graduate school, I’ve become really passionate
about science education and public outreach and the importance of giving back to
one’s community by passing on knowledge. I love talking to people about science,
whether it be my own work or something completely unrelated. Science (but
especially astronomy….though I may be biased :D ) is just so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked hard over the past several months to create this website and blog so
I can share my passion and 
excitement for science (mainly astronomy, but probably some other cool things
too!) with all of you. I’ve also created a travel blog to document my travels to
wherever astronomy takes me around the world (starting now….as my family and
friends already know, I’ve been several places already, including Chile and
several European countries…). You can get to both of these from the “Blogs”
tab at the top of the site. I hope you’ll find my blogs interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love, &lt;br /&gt;
~Stephanie~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/collage_of_me.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
