<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephanie Hamilton</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/</link>
    <description>This is the personal website of Stephanie Hamilton, graduate student at the University of Michigan</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 20:58:44 -0500</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day to Night and Back Again: The Great American Eclipse</title>
        <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/great-american-eclipse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/great-american-eclipse/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just…wow. I feel like I’ve been saying this for the past several years with
all of the amazing traveling I’ve been fortunate to do during my physics career,
but this was honestly one of the coolest experiences I’ve had. There are simply
no words to describe witnessing a total solar eclipse, but I’ll try my best
anyway!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve witnessed a couple of partial eclipses in the past, but being present for a
total solar eclipse was a top item on my bucket list. I had been anticipating
the eclipse of August 21, 2017 for &lt;em&gt;years,&lt;/em&gt; and I knew I had to be in the path
of totality when the time finally came. Everything seemed to fall perfectly into
place within the last few months leading up to the eclipse (and the last year,
really) – my boyfriend’s best friend moved to Seattle to take a job at SpaceX,
my cousin moved to central Oregon within an hour’s drive of the path of
totality, and the eclipse was due to happen within a week of both my and my
boyfriend’s birthdays. Honestly, I think the universe would have struck me down
if I &lt;em&gt;hadn’t&lt;/em&gt; booked a trip to the Pacific Northwest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-1-seattle-washington&quot;&gt;Stop #1: Seattle, Washington&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My boyfriend and I began our Pacific Northwest tour with four days in Seattle,
complete with walking around the city, a baseball game, museums, and hiking. Our
Seattle hosts showed us around Pike Place Market during our first afternoon in the
city after treating us to a delicious brunch. Afterward, we headed to the
Starbucks Roastery (of course I had to get fresh Starbucks coffee in
Seattle!). The rest of the day was spent enjoying ice cream and good drinks
before heading to a Mariners baseball game. Our weekend concluded with  another
delicious brunch, a tour of the
(outside of the) SpaceX complex in Redmond, WA, and exploring the flight museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While our hosts worked during the day on Monday and Tuesday, my boyfriend and I
took the opportunity to do some touristy things in Seattle: go up in the Space
Needle, walk through the Chihuly Glass Museum, and see the Olympic Sculpture
Park. After a 13+ mile day of walking, naturally we then had to do a four-mile
hike to Rattlesnake Ledge the following day, in the mountains outside of
Seattle. Even though our
feet were screaming at us a bit, the hike was definitely worth it and the view
from the ledge was fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/rattlesnake_ledge2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%&quot; alt=&quot;View from Rattlesnake Ledge.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a final night with our hosts in Seattle before picking up a rental car
and making the 6 hour drive down to Bend, OR, where we would stay with my cousin
and prepare for the eclipse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-2-bend-oregon&quot;&gt;Stop #2: Bend, Oregon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better way to spend a couple of days in Bend than touring breweries?
Unfortunately, we didn’t get to traverse the infamous “Bend Ale Trail,” though
we did check off a few of the breweries on the list during our dinner
outings. During our two days in Bend, however, while my cousin and her boyfriend were
working, my boyfriend and I took advantage of the endless outdoorsy options for
things to do. Our first day was spent hiking in Smith Rock State Park (after
sleeping in quite a bit in the morning…). Let me tell you, the Misery Ridge
Trail lived up to its name. Luckily we chose to hike the correct direction
around the loop – we conquered the bulk of the difficult climbing at
the beginning and enjoyed a relatively easy and
leisurely hike around the ridge and back down the other side. I definitely would
not have wanted to hike in the other direction! Anyway, the views were amazing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/rattlesnake_ledge.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: --&gt;
&lt;!-- left; width: 43%; margin-left: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The --&gt;
&lt;!-- Sun's corona and the black disk of the Moon.&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/rattlesnake_ledge2.jpg&quot; --&gt;
&lt;!-- style=&quot;float: right; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; --&gt;
&lt;!-- title=&quot;The landscape during totality.&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/misery_ridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from Misery Ridge.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of our second day in Bend was spent at the Lava Lands National
Park, where we toured the awesome site of a volcanic eruption dated to around
7,000 years ago. Even after all that time, there is still hardly anything living
in the basalt fields! We then rode a shuttle to the rim of the volcanic cinder
cone, where wildlife still existed and the huge, vast expanse of the lava field was
visible. Sort of. Unfortunately, smoke from the Milli Wildfire in Sisters, OR
had been blown directly over where we were. Not only did the smoke partly
conceal what was surely an awesome view, but it also made it hard to breathe. We
returned back to Bend to take a nice float down the Deschutes River in a tube,
and then it was time to pack for our journey to the path of totality! (…that
would make a great movie title!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-the-path-of-totality&quot;&gt;In the Path of Totality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of the solar eclipse didn’t truly start to set in for me until the
four of us officially set out from Bend on Saturday, August 19th to secure a
campsite in the path of totality. I could feel my excitement building up, and
that feeling didn’t go away for the subsequent few days. We wound our way
through the Oregon high desert, heading north and east out of the smoke cloud
emanating from the Milli Wildfire near Bend. Our destination was Hamilton, OR,
in honor of my cousin’s and my last names! Unfortunately, Hamilton was quite a
bit farther than we originally anticipated, so we stopped early and were
fortunate enough to secure one of the last campsites at a county park near
Fossil, OR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a full week of exploring (for my boyfriend and I) and work (for my cousin
and her boyfriend), we were pretty content with relaxing and being disconnected
from the busy world outside of our campsite. We spent the subsequent day and a
half lying in our hammocks or chatting around the picnic table, with a short
break to hike up a nearby hill and scope out our viewing spot for the
eclipse. The hike was made considerably more interesting by the fact that it
went through a cattle range – the cowpies were practically endless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were up and moving bright and early at 8am on August 21st. While the partial
phase of the eclipse didn’t start until after 9am and the hike up the hill only
took about 20 minutes, I couldn’t wait to get up there! Though, of course, once
we were finally at our viewing spot the subsequent hour-long wait was a bit
painful…but with eclipse glasses in hand, we started watching the sun for
signs of the moon’s shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-eclipse&quot;&gt;The Eclipse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first third of the partial phase (about 20 minutes), there was
practically no difference on Earth aside from the fact that there was a very
obvious chunk of the sun missing when viewed through the eclipse glasses. Then,
however, the air began to feel a bit cooler and the wind started to pick up. The
changing temperature was particularly noticeable in the desert because of the
lack of humidity in the air. By the final 20 minutes of the partial phase, it
was becoming quite chilly and my eyes could discern a very slight darkening of
the world around me. The sensation is difficult to describe – it almost felt as
if something was a bit “off” with my eyes, like they weren’t quite working
properly. It continued to get cooler as the moon continued to slide over the
face of the sun, while the sky remained ever so slightly darker than a bright
day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last five minutes (read: &lt;em&gt;five minutes!&lt;/em&gt;) of the partial phase were
incredible, second only to the minute and a half of totality itself. During
these five minutes, we could watch the last bit of the crescent sun sliding away
(through our glasses, of course). Things began to feel very eery as the world
prepared for sunset at 10:30am – in those moments, I completely understood why
solar eclipses have the reputation they do in ancient stories. It must have been
terrifying to witness the sky darken and the sun blink out in the middle of the
day! The sky quickly grew noticeably darker as the temperature continued to
drop. In the last moments before totality, we easily spotted Venus shining
brightly overhead. I put on my glasses one last time to watch the last sliver of
the sun disappear…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene that met my eyes when I removed my glasses is burned forever into my
memory. The sky had taken on a bluish-black color characteristic of late
evening, while the reds and oranges of sunset were visible around the full 360
degrees of the horizon. But most amazing of all was the sun – it was covered
completely by the impossibly black disk of the moon, leaving the white, wispy
corona to shine brilliantly in a beautiful halo against the blue-black sky. I
couldn’t take my eyes away from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/total_eclipse.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 43%; margin-left: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Sun's corona and the black disk of the Moon.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/PNW2017/total_eclipse_landscape.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 49%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The landscape during totality.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All too soon, a mere 90 seconds later, the famous “diamond ring” reappeared: the
sun was returning, with its light overwhelming the corona and the black disk of
the moon in a matter of seconds. My cousin, me, and our boyfriends all turned
toward each other with expressions of “That was amazing!” written on our
faces. To be honest, it was considerably more than “amazing.” I wasn’t kidding
when I said there aren’t words to describe it! There is simply no comparison
between a total eclipse and a partial eclipse – during a parital eclipse, you
never get the drastic darkening of the sky, the experience of seeing stars
during the day, the overwhelming excitement caused by knowing what these eery
phenomena are leading to, or the image of a black moon surrounded by the
brilliant white corona. All I can say is that I will definitely be in the path
of totatilty for the next total eclipse in the US in April 2024, and you should
be too!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Astronomy, Telescopes, and Bears, Oh My! (Part 2)</title>
        <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/astronomy-telescopes-bears-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/astronomy-telescopes-bears-part-2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 2 of my blog series documenting my amazing time as an instructor
of a ground-based astronomy course based at Kitt Peak National Observatory in
Tucson, AZ! If you missed
&lt;a href=&quot;http://stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/astronomy-telescopes-bears-part-1/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;,
be sure to head over there and check out that
post before you jump into this one! If you haven’t browsed through &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/photos/scwjXSo7fZ74gmFy7&quot;&gt;my photo
album of the trip&lt;/a&gt;, you should do that
also! And without further ado…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tuesday-may-16th&quot;&gt;Tuesday, May 16th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may recall from Part 1, we had the last night of our observing run at
the 2.4m and 1.3m telescopes at the MDM Observatory on Sunday night, meaning
Monday night was the first night back on a normal sleep schedule. Because of
this, there were no activities scheduled on Tuesday morning, but everyone was
pretty antsy for Tuesday afternoon’s activity. Why, you ask? Well, we were
taking a trip to the Arizona Desert Museum – that’s right, we were leaving the
mountain for the first time in about 10 days! As much as I loved being up at the
summit of Kitt Peak, I was also ready for a change in scenery, even if it was
only going to be for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of the word “museum,” I generally think of various exhibits
arranged in a strategic way inside a giant building. The Arizona Desert Museum
was about as far from that as one can get – the entire museum was outdoors! I
would have called it more of a zoo, actually, with different plants and animals
native to desert ecosystems as the exhibits. Consequently, it was unlike any zoo
I’ve ever been in. First of all, it was located in the mountains north of
Tucson, meaning that at certain points within the museum there were fabulous
views of the desert landscape in and around Tucson. Second, how often does one
walk through a museum or a zoo that has cacti everywhere? (Side note: there were
also little baby cacti in tiny pots in the gift shop! No, I wasn’t tempted at
all…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first exhibit we walked through was a hummingbird exhibit, with the
hummingbirds freely flying around and only a net keeping them from escaping the
exhibit. I seem to recall having to duck out of the way of at least one
hummingbird that zoomed right by my head…that was certainly the
most…interactive….exhibit we encountered! We continued around the museum,
seeing everything from birds to wolves to even some otters. The exhibit I was
most excited for, though, was the black bear exhibit (especially after all the
hype about the black bear roaming the summit of Kitt Peak). As per my luck,
naturally there was no black bear visible when we arrived at the
exhibit. However, our patience was rewarded and a few minutes later we spotted
a bear lumbering around in the shadows! I was quite glad that this was the only
black bear I ended up seeing during my whole stay at Kitt Peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day ended with stopping for some delicious Mexican food and a margarita
before continuing on to the mountain for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/desert_museum_pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the desert museum&quot; title=&quot;View from the desert museum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/desert_museum_blackbear.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 45%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Black bear in the desert museum&quot; title=&quot;Black bear in the desert museum&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/desert_museum_cacti.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 45%; margin-left: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Cacti in the desert museum&quot; title=&quot;Cacti in the desert museum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wednesday-may-17th&quot;&gt;Wednesday, May 17th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday began with a lecture on optical and infrared telescopes. We talked
about how telescopes direct light to
magnify distant objects, the different ways one can construct a telescope, and
the pros and cons of each telescope design. You might not know that there
are at least five different basic telescope designs, each with their own
pros and cons!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- The students then learned about the different ways to mount a --&gt;
&lt;!-- telescope and corresponding pros and cons of each mounting method. Think about --&gt;
&lt;!-- this: would you want to have a telescope that rotates with the Earth, or would --&gt;
&lt;!-- you rather have a telescope that you can spin around on the ground and point up --&gt;
&lt;!-- at a target? Well, that depends on what you're studying, right? If you want to --&gt;
&lt;!-- track your target as the Earth rotates, it might be easier to just use the --&gt;
&lt;!-- Earth's rotation axis as one of the telescope's rotation axes -- that is, one --&gt;
&lt;!-- telescope axis will be pointing toward the North Star, for example. Check out my --&gt;
&lt;!-- Part 1 post for more discussion about telescope mounts! --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing up the lecture talking about differences in telescope tubes and
sizes and summarizing all of the major telescopes that have been built or are in
the works, we took another tour of the WIYN and Mayall telescopes. This time, we
were focusing on the physical construction of the scopes – mounts, structure,
tubes, and the like. While at the 4-m Mayall telescope, our guide brought the
telescope to its “service position” so that we could clearly see the
mirror and the inner workings. We also got to climb into the “Cassegrain Cage,”
or the chamber-like space at the bottom of the telescope below the mirror. Let me tell you, it’s
a bit disconcerting sitting down there knowing there’s a 30-ton mirror and all
of the other metal and telescope structure right above your head…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/cassegraincage.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 24%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;The Cassegrain cage from afar&quot; title=&quot;The Cassegrian cage from afar&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/cassegraincage_inside.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: center; width: 37%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Inside the Cassegrain cage&quot; title=&quot;Inside the Cassegrain cage&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/mayallmirror.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 37%; margin-left: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;View of the Mayall 4-m mirror&quot; title=&quot;View of the Mayall 4-m mirror&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday-may-18th&quot;&gt;Thursday, May 18th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two off-mountain excursions within three days?! This is &lt;em&gt;madness!&lt;/em&gt; Yes, that’s
right, we got to leave the mountain again! This excursion was pretty cool – we
got to go to the CCD lab and the mirror lab to learn about how the camera CCD
detectors and the mirrors of telescopes are made!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop was the CCD lab. We were actually very fortunate to get a full
tour of the lab, thanks to Sally’s connections at the University of Arizona –
they usually don’t take groups back into the lab to see the CCD-making process
up close and personal. But we got to see everything! Dr. Mike Lesser was our
guide for the morning and he first showed us the chemical treatment baths used
to treat and finish the freshly made CCD detector chips. So I guess we started
the tour with a major spoiler alert, seeing the final step of manufacture
first. We then got to see how the silicon pieces arrive at the lab (roughly cut
to size but definitely not in their final shapes), how the tiny micro/nano-scale
electronics are installed, how the chips are tested for quality (we saw the
testing of CCDs that will be installed on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Large_Synoptic_Survey_Telescope&quot;&gt;LSST&lt;/a&gt;!), and finally
what they look like once they are finished. I even got to take a selfie in one
of the biggest CCD chips ever made!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/ccdchip_selfie.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 34%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Selfie in one of the biggest CCD chips ever made&quot; title=&quot;Selfie in one of the biggest CCD chips ever made&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/ccdchip_lsst.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 59%; margin-left: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Testing CCD chips for LSST&quot; title=&quot;Testing CCD chips for LSST&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some delicious Chicago-style pizza for lunch, it was time to visit the
mirror lab! Except, not quite…we were a little early, so we decided to check
out the planetarium at the University of Arizona. Not a bad way to kill an extra
hour! I was pretty excited, though, once we made our way over to the Steward
Observatory Mirror Lab. I’ve long been curious how the heck one would make a
giant, 4-, 6-, or 8-m mirror that is flatter than the US would be if you blew
everything up to that scale. And how one would accomplish this without breaking
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that there is a single company that makes the special type of glass
needed for telescope mirrors. Which is pretty scary, because if that
company goes under then we wouldn’t know where to get the glass we need…I’ll
just hope that doesn’t happen! Anyway, this lab made the LSST 8-m mirror, but
unfortunately it had already started its journey down to Chile by the time we
took our tour. However, they are currently casting the mirrors for another huge
telescope, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giant_Magellan_Telescope&quot;&gt;Giant Magellan Telescope&lt;/a&gt;,
which will consist of &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; 8-m
mirrors in an array. Just let that sink in for a second….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the basic process for casting your very own giant telescope mirror!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first thing that happens is a mold is made for the size and shape the
mirror is supposed to be. Many mirrors nowadays are made in the “honeycomb”
style – hollow hexagonal tube structures make up the backside of the mirror,
which drastically cuts down on the amount of glass in and the weight of the
final mirror.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then the mold (which
can be 8 meters in diameter, remember!) is hand packed full of chunks of
that special glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The technicians build an oven around the mold. Yes, you
read that right. This oven gets up to several thousands of degrees Celsius and
the mold spins for somewhere around three days (the exact rate of spinning is
determined by the final desired curvature of the mirror).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carefully&lt;/em&gt; slow down the spinning and cool the furnace for 100 days. Yes,
that is &lt;em&gt;one hundred days&lt;/em&gt;. This is a very delicate process! We don’t want
&lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; deformations at all in the final, cooled piece of glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick up your several-tens-of-tons piece of glass and move it to the grinding
and polishing station. &lt;em&gt;Whatever you do, don’t drop it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind and polish for weeks. Literally. Remember, everything needs to be
smoother than the continental US!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the polishing is complete, the proto-mirror is packaged and sent on to
its destination, where it will be coated in reflective aluminum and installed
on the telescope!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend reading
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lsst.org/sites/default/files/docs/CastTwoMirrorsUANews.pdf&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;
about the casting of the LSST mirrors – the scale of the process is astounding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/mirrorlab.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;
margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;At the UofA mirror lab, seeing manufacture of GMT mirrors&quot; title=&quot;At the UofA mirror lab, seeing manufacture of GMT mirrors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day ended with shadowing a couple of observers at the 4-m Mayall telescope,
one of whom was my own advisor at Michigan! It was a little weird seeing
him and catching up on two weeks of research on the other side of the
country…anyway, the students got some more insight into the exciting lives of
21st century astronomers – that is, watching multiple computer screens to
monitor the telescope, data quality, and any alerts that might come up. That’s a
little different from how things were even 30 years ago, when astronomers worked
in rooms just off the main telescope room that had windows so they could see the
telescope itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friday-may-19th&quot;&gt;Friday, May 19th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday was another exciting day with another cool tour of one of the telescopes
at Kitt Peak. This time, it was of a radio telescope with a 12-m dish (think
satellite TV dish, except 10 times bigger). After a morning lecture about radio
astronomy, we made the short drive over to the ARO radio telescope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cool thing about radio astronomy is that is doesn’t have to be done only at
night – you can observe radio targets during the day! Consequently, this is
also why all cell phones have to be set to airplane mode on the Kitt Peak summit,
because you never know when the radio astronomers will be observing. All of this
meant that when we showed up for our tour at 1pm, the astronomers were prepping
the telescope to start observations. Don’t worry, though, we still had plenty of
time to explore the telescope (including climbing inside its Cassegrain cage
equivalent!) before the actual observations started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tidbits you might not know about radio telescopes and astronomy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radio telescopes don’t actually need domes! The ARO telescope only does
because they wanted a little more protection from the elements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radio dishes are made out of carbon fiber and coated with nickel. Some of the
largest ones can even be made out of mesh or chicken wire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The resolution of the telescope is inversely proportional to its size – that
is, larger telescopes have coarser resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ARO telescope uses a prototype dish for the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atacama_Large_Millimeter_Array&quot;&gt;ALMA telescope&lt;/a&gt;
in Chile, one of
the premier radio telescope facilities in the world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/aro_radioscope.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;
margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;The ARO radio telescope from outside the dome&quot; title=&quot;The ARO radio telescope from outside the dome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saturday-may-20th&quot;&gt;Saturday, May 20th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight was finally the night of the Alumni Star Party! This event invites UofM
alumni (mostly local, but a couple of professors from UofM flew to Tucson for
the party) to a reception and a chance to observe through an eyepiece through
the 1.3m and 2.4m telescopes that the students used to take their data. With a
list of targets in hand, including planets, galaxies, and nebulae, we began
directing the telescope as one of the UofM professors explained the science and
history behind the particular target we were looking at. We got to see Jupiter,
its moons, Saturn and its rings, the Andromeda galaxy, and even a comet! All in
all, it was a really awesome experience meeting these distinguished alumni of
UofM and showing them some cool astronomy objects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/jupiter.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 30%; margin-left: 15%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Jupiter as viewed through the 1.3-m McGraw-Hill telescope&quot; title=&quot;Jupiter as viewed through the 1.3-m McGraw-Hill telescope&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/saturn.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 32%; margin-right: 15%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;Saturn as viewed through the 1.3-m McGraw-Hill telescope&quot; title=&quot;Saturn as viewed through the 1.3-m McGraw-Hill telescope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-may-21st&quot;&gt;Sunday, May 21st&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew, another free day…after a busy week, it was nice to have a day off to do
some more exploring! After relaxing a bit and eating some lunch, I started
making my way to a trail I found out about by talking to one of the Kitt
Peak staff members. I had been craving some good rock climbing and hiking since I arrived
at Kitt Peak! With a book in hand (well, backpack actually), I set off
through the woods with the intent of climbing some rocks, gosh darn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to report that I was successful in that endeavor! There is a very
prominent rock formation that is visible from many sites on Kitt Peak, and the
trail went right to it. I had a great couple of hours exploring every nook and
cranny of those rocks, climbing right to the tippy-top (sorry Mom!) and enjoying
my book with the valley splayed out way below me. I even made a lizard friend
while I was up there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/kittpeak_rockclimbing.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 40%; margin-left: 5%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;View from Kitt Peak&quot; title=&quot;View from Kitt Peak&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/lizard.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right; width: 40%; margin-right: 5%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;A new lizard friend!&quot; title=&quot;A new lizard friend!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and stay tuned for Part 3 in this series!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Astronomy, Telescopes, and Bears, Oh My! (Part 1)</title>
        <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/astronomy-telescopes-bears-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/astronomy-telescopes-bears-part-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;….ok, I never actually saw the bear….but we were thoroughly warned before
(and after) we arrived at the mountain that there was a resident black bear
roaming the premises. And I can confirm that the bear was sighted during the
time we were there, though not by anyone in our group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This May, I had the fantastic opportunity to travel to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noao.edu/kpno/&quot;&gt;Kitt Peak National
Observatory&lt;/a&gt;, located about 50 miles southwest of
Tucson, AZ, to teach a great
group of undergraduates about ground-based observatories. Over the course of
four short weeks, the students developed a science idea to test, wrote a
telescope observing proposal based on that idea, took their own data using
two telescopes at Kitt Peak, reduced and analyzed the data, and presented
their results. And this was all done while having to sit in lectures, go
on tours (both on the Kitt Peak site and off), and participate in several other
off-site excursions! Thinking back, it’s really amazing how much the students
were able to accomplish, and to such a high standard! (Can you tell I’m proud of
them?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an instructor, I was fortunate enough to get an all-expenses-paid
trip (plus a paycheck!) to a gorgeous mountaintop with greenery and wildlife,
awesome telescopes, and beautiful sunsets. It was probably the best experience
I’ve had in graduate school so far, so I am writing this blog post to
memorialize it and share it with all of you! I’ll be splitting this experience
into several posts, due to the jam-packed schedule and sheer number of
things we were able to do and see over the course of our month at Kitt Peak. So
stay tuned for subsequent posts in this series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and make sure you check out my photos, too!  &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-long-arrow-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/photos/scwjXSo7fZ74gmFy7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stephanie’s
Obnoxiously Long Kitt Peak Photo Album&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunday-may-7th&quot;&gt;Sunday, May 7th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After pretty smooth travels (aside from a two hour delay in Minneapolis) I
FINALLY arrived in Tucson! This was my first time in Southern Arizona, so I was
excited to see this new place. Of course, the first thing I noticed was all of
the brown – brown ground, brown trees, brown weeds….and then Sally (the
professor of the class) said as we were driving up Kitt Peak the first time,
“Wow, it’s pretty green here still!”…WHAT? After she said it, I could see some
green in there,
but coming from Michigan pretty much anything else seems brown by comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The students were assigned dorm rooms in pairs, while Sally and I would be
staying in the guest house on site. Accommodations were basically what you’d
expect from a facility constructed in
the 1960s – wood paneled walls, fluffy carpet, a single ethernet modem that was
very obviously wired after the house was built….not even kidding, there was an
obvious hole in the exterior wall. Nonetheless, I was happy to be staying in a
place with my own bedroom, a kitchen, and internet access (evidently the dorm
where the students stayed didn’t even have ethernet! #firstworldproblems?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After settling in a bit, we all piled
into our giant 15-passenger van (a completely necessary vehicle with 12 students
and 2 instructors, thankfully I didn’t have to drive it) and headed to one of
the two telescopes we would be using the following weekend (the
Hiltner 2.4-meter and the McGraw-Hill 1.3-meter) to shadow an
astronomer who was using it for the night. It was actually super cool to see
astronomy behind-the-scenes on the very first night at the observatory! We
didn’t hang around too long though, due to our jet-lagged brains screaming at us
for being awake at (what felt like) 3am…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/mayall_bw.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Mayall 4m, KPNO.&quot; alt=&quot;The Mayall 4m, KPNO.&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monday-may-8th&quot;&gt;Monday, May 8th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 of class was pretty uneventful, with a general introduction to the site and the
structure of the class. In general, each day consisted of an AM, PM, and evening
activity – these consisted primarily of lectures and site tours toward the
beginning, but transitioned to more off-site excursions toward the end. More
on those later! We were welcomed to the observatory by none other than the
director herself, Lori Allen (side note: how awesome is it that the director of
a major American astronomical observatory is a woman?!). We learned from her the
difficulties that come with funding an observatory whose largest telescopes are
now considered painfully mid-sized, and all of the hoops they need to jump
through. The National Science Foundation was actually about to close this
historic and beautiful observatory until its largest telescope was chosen to be
used for a huge upcoming survey,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Energy_Spectroscopic_Instrument&quot;&gt;DESI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tuesday-may-9th&quot;&gt;Tuesday, May 9th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 was a bit more interesting than Day 1, with tours to two of the bigger
telescopes on site planned – the 2.3-meter WIYN telescope and the 4-meter
Mayall telescope (where DESI will be installed). These two scopes are quite
different in their designs; for example, the Mayall lives in an 18-story
concrete/metal building, while the WIYN lives in a 4 story building….this has
to do primarily with the way the telescopes are mounted and controlled. In the
old days before advanced computers, it was much easier to align one of the telescope’s
axes of motion with Earth’s axis of rotation. This way, when an astronomer was
tracking an object across the sky, she only had to worry about a single axis of
rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with this design is that by having one axis aligned with Earth’s
rotational axis, one ends up with the weight of the telescope somewhat suspended
in midair. Consequently, the supports for the telescope need to be much bigger
in order to securely support its weight. A better design is one that
doesn’t have to fight gravity as
much – instead, have one axis be horizontal to the ground (like a
merry-go-round) and have the second axis be a simple up-and-down
movement. Unfortunately, this design was not practical until more advanced
computers came along that could precisely control the two axes simultaneously in order
to track an object across the sky. Now that that’s possible, however, telescopes
built today use this second design. The pictures below show these two designs:
on the left is the first and on the right is the second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/mayall_mount.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 53%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;The Mayall 4m, KPNO&quot; title=&quot;The Mayall 4m, KPNO&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/wiyn.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 43%; margin-right: 1%; margin-bottom: 0.5em;&quot; alt=&quot;The WIYN 2.3m, KPNO&quot; title=&quot;The WIYN 2.3m, KPNO&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up the rest of the day with a couple of lectures and a meal in the
cafeteria. I have to say, I was very pleasantly surprised by the quality of the
food up at the summit – I had heard horror stories about the cafeteria-grade food
by some colleagues, but
I enjoyed every meal throughout the month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wednesday-may-10th&quot;&gt;Wednesday, May 10th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think by the third day, the students were starting to become aware of the work
that would be required of them during the month…this was the day they needed
to choose a telescope on-site that they would write five pages about, with only a couple of
days until their project observing proposals were due, complete from choosing a
topic to study to determining the amount
of time and the instruments they would need on the telescopes to describing the science
product they expected to obtain at the end. Let’s just say I much preferred the
instructor role, available to help when needed but also able to sit under a tree
with a book when I wanted…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, we had the chance to head over to one of telescopes we’d be
using in just a couple of days, the McGraw-Hill 1.3-meter at the
MDM observatory
(fun fact: “MDM” stands for MIT, Dartmouth, and Michigan, in honor of the
founding institutions of this subset of telescopes. MIT has since left the
collaboration, and the remaining institutions have been joined by Ohio State,
Ohio University, and Columbia University. Yet it’s still called
MDM…astronomers, I tell ya). Was this the start of our observing run? No,
actually we were going to watch an astronomer at the University of Michigan
begin his night of observing from the comfort of his own office. This “remote
observing” is quite bizarre to witness – imagine you’re sitting in a room
surrounded by the computers that control the telescope, yet the mouse is moving
on its own, the lights in the dome turn on and off by themselves, and the
telescope just starts moving….yes, obviously there was a human controlling
these things, but it was strange knowing they were doing so from 2,000 miles away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thursday-may-11th&quot;&gt;Thursday, May 11th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday was a pretty chill day overall, at least for Sally and I. For the
students, it was a combination of stressful in the morning as they put the
finishing touches on their observing proposal drafts and relaxation/decompression
after said stress. The afternoon saw a brief lecture from me, but the evening is
when the real fun started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We piled into our 15-passenger van once again (this became a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; common
theme throughout the month…I had a love/hate relationship with that van) and
made our way to the MDM observatory to get familiar with the instruments we’d be
using. We of course watched the
sunset before getting to work, as all astronomers do (what can we say, they
never get old!). I’ve come to the conclusion that no sunset compares to those
seen from mountain tops in the desert – the reddened sunlight just mixes so
perfectly with the dusty brown/red landscape, and mountains are always gorgeous
photo targets. I have no idea how many sunset pictures I took over the course of
the month, but this one has to be my favorite:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/sunset_pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at MDM&quot; title=&quot;Sunset at MDM&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sunset, we began standard procedures to prepare the telescopes for a
night of observing. We weren’t officially scheduled to begin observing until
Friday night, but we wanted to be familiar with the instruments and procedures
before we actually had to do it for real. I took the helm at the 1.3m, while
Sally was in control at the 2.4m. The start up and shut down procedures became
second nature by the end of our four nights at the scopes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill the detector dewar with liquid nitrogen in order to keep it cold all
night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open exterior doors to the dome to equilibrate the air temperature inside the
dome and reduce turbulence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the dome shutter, then open the telescope mirror covers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open any field stops to ensure light can reach the detector.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell the telescope to begin tracking Earth’s rotation. Then, move to a bright
star and ensure the telescope is pointing where it thinks it is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Observe!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform 1–5 in reverse to shut down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was after 2am by the time we had ironed out any kinks in the procedures and
gained confidence in operating the telescopes, so with an unplanned half-night
of observing under our belts, we went to bed eagerly anticipating our full
weekend of observing ahead. Or, at least, I was – I’ve come to really enjoy
staying up all night in the peaceful company of other astronomers and with the
ability to go outside and see incredible night skies whenever I want. Maybe I’m
crazy, or maybe I’m just meant to be an astronomer. There’s
nothing like it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday-may-12th--monday-may-15th&quot;&gt;Friday, May 12th – Monday, May 15th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooray, it was finally observing weekend! Granted, we had literally all of
Friday to get through first, and maybe I was the only one actually excited about
staying up all night to operate a multi-million-dollar instrument, but I think
the students were eager as well….at the very least to operate said
instruments. After submitting final drafts of their observing proposals and a
lecture from me, and after arming ourselves with snacks and coffee, we were
ready for our first full night of observing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We watched sunset, as per usual, and then dispersed to our selected telescopes
– I was again in charge of the smaller 1.3m telescope, while the majority of the
students opted to use the 2.4m. Aside from being bigger, the 2.4m had different
instruments installed that would perform spectroscopy (essentially decomposing
all of the light from a source into the amount of light per wavelength), which
most of the students’ projects required. This all meant that my job was actually
pretty easy! Things went smoothly the whole night, at least at the 1.3m, and I
was glad that the first
observing experience (ever, for some of the students) went so well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up around 5:30am (I know, crazy), and then slept until the next
afternoon. I always feel extremely lazy when observing because I wake up at 2pm
or later, even though I stay up until 5:30 or 6am…I’m a night owl for sure,
but definitely not nocturnal! Anyway, Saturday afternoon was our mock Telescope
Allocation Committee (TAC)…even though we had observed already…oh well, the
schedule can always be adjusted! The purpose of the TAC is to evaluate all
observing proposals submitted, discuss strengths and weaknesses along with the
impact of each, and then give each proposal an overall score. In our class, the top-ranked
proposals then got the amount of time at the time of night they requested, while
the lower-ranked proposals did not get all of the time they asked for (in the
real world, the bottom-ranked proposals don’t get any time at all, if the
telescope gets filled up!). I was incredibly impressed with the level of the
discussions by the students about each proposal – Sally even said that it was
at the level of a real TAC! Our observing schedule was modified slightly based
on the evaluations of our mock TAC, and then it was nap time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday night went pretty much exactly how Friday went – gorgeous sunset,
smooth observing, watched a couple of movies (animated Pixar films, obviously!), and
wrapped up around 6am. After waking up in the mid-afternoon on Sunday, I decided
it was about time I explored the summit a bit, so I took my book and set off to
find the perfect secluded reading spot. And oh, did I find it! Look at this
view! I definitely went back here several times during the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/KPNO17/pano_mcgrath_elderbrother.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The view looking south from the Kitt Peak summit.&quot; alt=&quot;The view looking south from the Kitt Peak summit.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday night was much more of the same, and again we slept until
mid-afternoon on Monday. I was so glad our observing runs went so incredibly
smoothly! That all too often seems not to be the case, whether it’s because of
some technical failure, a software error, or just Mother Nature. After a lecture
and dinner, we all had Monday night off
and were able to finally try to adjust back to normal sleeping hours. This is
actually starting to become second nature to me…every time I go observing, it
seems like I adjust to the opposite schedule even faster than the last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think I’ll wrap this post up here. I hope you’re enjoying reading about my
Kitt Peak adventure so far! I’ll be back soon with the next post in this series,
in which we actually get to leave the mountain after 10 straight days on the
summit. Though to be honest, I was quite happy to return to 6750 feet after only
a short time in the desert heat…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until my next post, friends!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <link>https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.stephaniejhamilton.com/blog/hello/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi! I’m Stephanie, a high-energy-physicist-turned-astronomer working toward my
Ph.D. at the University of Michigan. I’ve had a non-linear path to becoming an
astronomer, even though astronomy has been my passion since about the sixth
grade. Better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to find myself studying the Solar System, and more specifically the
small objects that orbit within a donut-shaped ring farther out than Neptune. While
this isn’t what I’d pictured myself studying when I began graduate school, I
honestly wouldn’t want to be studying anything else! These small, seemingly
insignificant bodies in the distant reaches of the Solar System actually hold
the key to unlocking its entire history! The much larger gas giant planets
easily fling them about, so by discovering many of them and watching how they
move, we can try to make educated guesses as to what types of interactions
happened in their pasts. I think that’s what I find so cool and
exciting about my research – we are pushing the limits of the best telescopes
and cameras on Earth to search for objects that are a fraction of the size of
Earth and farther away than Pluto or the New Horizons spacecraft. It’s truly amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my time so far in graduate school, I’ve become really passionate
about science education and public outreach and the importance of giving back to
one’s community by passing on knowledge. I love talking to people about science,
whether it be my own work or something completely unrelated. Science (but
especially astronomy….though I may be biased :D ) is just so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked hard over the past several months to create this website and blog so
I can share my passion and
excitement for science (mainly astronomy, but probably some other cool things
too!) with all of you. I’ve also created a travel blog to document my travels to
wherever astronomy takes me around the world (starting now….as my family and
friends already know, I’ve been several places already, including Chile and
several European countries…). You can get to both of these from the “Blogs”
tab at the top of the site. I hope you’ll find my blogs interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love, &lt;br /&gt;
~Stephanie~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/collage_of_me.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
